注意有海盜
Attention, pirates alongside!
注意有海盜 進入船艙躲避
Pirates alongside! Take cover. All crew below deck!
再說一遍 注意有海盜
I repeat Pirates alongside!
執行緊急措施
Initiate emergency procedure!
所有船員到船艙躲避
All crew below deck!
緊急措施 紅色警報
Emergency positions! Code red! Code red!
所有船員到船艙躲避
Get everybody below deck, now!
所有人趴下
Everyone, get down!
傑克 聯合國護衛艦在哪?
Jack, where's that UN convoy?
直升機起飛了 三十分鐘到
The chopper's on its way,sir. ETA 30 minutes!
所有人躲避到艙裡
Get everybody below deck
我在等俺兒子啊
I'm waiting for my son
我不能讓他回來找不著家啊
I need our home for his return!
等員警來了 我看你們還敢不敢拆
Wait till police get here! Let's see how you're going to tear our houses!
想死就別攔著
If they wanna die, then let 'em
嬸 嫂子
Mrs. Yu, Mrs.Fei.
我們把小飛送回來了
We brought Xiao Fei home
敬禮
Salute!
告訴新來的 俺們中隊的座右銘是啥啊?
Tell these rookies what our motto is
謙虛
Be humble
我來當兵就是為了打仗
I became a soldier because I wanted to be in battles
現在呢 打啥仗啊打仗?
and now, what about the battles?
在家都陪陪老婆孩子多好啊
Much better to be at home with wife and kids instead
我閨女 漂亮吧?
My daughter, she's beautiful, huh?
一個個驢球馬蛋的啊
You gang of sumbags!
還真拿自己當回事了 是吧?
You think you're tough, huh?
給我打 都上
Go get them! Get them!
員警同志他有槍
Officer see! He's got a gun!
有槍
a gun!
解放軍同志 請你把槍放下
Comrade, put down your weapon!
挺能打是吧?
You're pretty lethal, huh?
咋不弄死我呢?
Well you'd better kill me now,
有不在的時候吧
because you're gone,
你看我怎麼弄死他們
I'm gonna make them wish they were dead
嘿
Hey!
冷鋒
Leng Feng!
軍人 之所以被人尊重
The reason a soldier is respected
不是因為軍人兩個字
is not because of the uniform he wears,
而是因為軍人擔負的責任
but is because of the sense of duty he carries
即使脫了軍裝 職責還在
With or without the uniform, the duty remains
一樣會被人尊重
And he continues to be respected
快點
Hey, hurry up!
嘿 冷 我們的英雄
Hey, Leng. There's our hero
感謝你救了我們大家
Thanks for saving the lives of everyone
- 我們合個影唄?- 沒問題
- Let's take a picture together - No problem!
- 謝謝 - 好的 再見
- Thank you! - Ok, see you!
再見 保重
Take care, see you!
嘿 老闆
Hey, boss!
- 買點吧 這是好東西 - 上次塔曼村疫情爆發
- Buy some, it's good stuff - There was an outbreak in Taman recently
就因為萬吃了這個藥材 有四個人活下來呢
Because of consuming this herbs, there were 4 survivors
- 拜託 - 不了 謝謝
- Please! - No, thank you!
幫幫忙吧 考慮一下
Please help please consider
老闆
Boss.
中國酒來了
Chinese wine.
這兒
This
- 嘿 - 別這樣兄弟
- Hey, hey. - Come on man
好吧 這次就算了
Ok, this one is okay
合作愉快 下次見
Nice one. See you next time.
上來
Get up here!
歡迎回來
Welcome back!
再見
Bye
這個 好東西
This, good for you
能讓你不再孤單
You're not alone
20美元 買一送一
20 dollars. Buy one get one free
- 我是誰 - 我的乾爹
- Who am I? - My godfather
如果乾爹把這個告訴你媽媽
If your godfather tells your mother about this,
她會怎麼想? 沒收了
what would she think? Confiscated!
開始
Begin!
乾爹 乾爹 乾爹
Godfather! Godfather! Godfather!
哈裡 哈裡 哈裡
Harry! Harry! Harry!
乾爹 乾爹 乾爹
Godfather! Godfather! Godfather!
阿冷 阿冷 阿冷
Leng! Leng! Leng!
誰?
Who?
還有誰? 還有誰?
Who else? Who else?
你上
Do it, do it
去你的
Fuck it!
你以為你是誰啊?
Who the fuck you think you are?
來吧
Come on!
好啊
Yeah
派翠克 派翠克 派翠克
Patrick! Patrick! Patrick!
我要去邊境執行一項任務
I've been sent to the border for a mission
等我回來的時候
When I get back,
希望你能在這個檔上簽字
this had better be signed
結婚申請
為什麼當兵?
Why did you join the army?
當兵後悔兩年 不當兵後悔一輩子
Join the army, you regret it for two years. Don't join the army, regret it for life.
- 真話?- 真話
- The truth? - That's the truth.
再喝
Drink! again!
龍小雲同志
Comrade Long Xiao Yun.
在邊境執行任務時不幸遇襲
was attacked while carrying her mission at the border.
在現場 我們發現了這枚子彈
We found this bullet.
再喝
Drink again.
你想聽什麼?
What do you want to hear?
再喝
Drink!
Again!
你贏了
You win.
我輸了...
But I lost...
徹徹底底的輸了
I've lost completely.
你跟船已經有一年多了
It's been more than a year since you came on board
從傑爾巴到藻拉納魯
During that time, from Djerba to Tolanaro,
大半個非洲的部落長老我都問過
I've asked all the chiefs. More than half of Africa,
都沒有見過你的這顆子彈
And nobody has seen that bullet before. peluru itu sebelumnya.
我一定會找到的
I will find it,
哪伯走遍整個非洲
even if I have to scour the entire continent.
親愛的祖國同胞們
Dear fellow countrymen,
首先我對貝卡村受難的同胞表示沉痛哀悼
my deepest condolences to the families their loved ones during Batchka Village incident
今日早些時候 非法武裝組織紅巾軍表示對貝其卡滅村行動負責
Early today, the red scarf rebel army claimed responsibility for the Batchka Village
我們對這種慘絕人寰的行為強烈譴責
Our government condemns their barbaric behavior.
我們的家園 正在遭受一連串的傷害
Our homeland has been attacked on multiple occasions.
不幸的事接二連三發生
These are great tragedies.
紅巾軍的恐怖勢力如同疫情一樣蔓延
The rebels continue to advance as the country grapples with the Lamanla outbreak.
政府不會坐以待斃 偉大的人民軍隊誓為家園奮戰到底
As your government, we will not back down. The great people's army will fight to the very end.
另外國家設立了疫情隔離區
Quarantine have been set up across the country,
最大範圍內控制了疫情造成的傷害
in an attempt to contain the Lamanla outbreak.
國家已經把醫療救助級別和緊急程度設為最高
We have declared a state of emergency.
哎 哥們
Hey, brother
少三張
You shorted me 300 bucks.
輕點兒
Be careful with that.
大家都是中國人
Look, we're both Chinese.
這樣好麼?
You do this to your own people?
我從上個月14號下午三點開始
Since 3 pm on the 14th of last month,
就不是中國人了
I am no longer officailly Chinese.
怎麼著?剛從國內來啊?
What? Fresh off the boat?
看見了麼? 現在這局勢
Hear that? In times like this,
就是這個價
that's the price you get.
見過這個麼?
Seen this before?
沒見過
Nope
有人說在這個國家出現過
I've been told that it came from these parts.
我真沒見過
Definitely never seen it.
老闆
Hey boss.
你怎麼樣了?來根煙?
How are you? Smoking?
土豆
Tundu!
走 走
Go! Go!
別開槍
Don't shoot!
- 別開槍 - 他們是好人
- Don't shoot! - Good people
過去 過去
Go, go, go!
想活的就給我趴下
Get the fuck down or you die!
- 紅巾軍必勝 - 你知道你在跟誰說話嗎
- Hail the revolution! - You're now talking to rebels!
不要騙我 你倒楣了
Don't lie to me. Your luck is down!
紅巾軍必勝
Hail the revolution!
不不不 快看
No, no, no Guys, look!
必勝
Revolution!
- 這他媽的是什麼? - 不不不
- What the fuck is this?! - No, no, no
他是政府軍的走狗
He's a pro-government rat!
- 不不不 - 你在騙我
- NO! - You lied to me!
不不不 紅巾軍必勝 紅巾軍必勝
No! Hail the rebels! Hail the rebels!
媽的
Shit!
土豆
Tundu!
- 中國大使館 - 去大使館
- Chinese embassy - Let's go to the Chinese embassy.
他們會收留我們的 我們是中國人
They'll take us in. We're Chinese.
那我們怎麼辦? 我們該怎麼辦?
What about us? What're we suppose to do?
- 他們會收留我們嗎?- 很難說
- Will they accept us? - Hard to say.
- 那是我們的國家 - 所有人跟我走
- That's our country. - Everybody follow me.
走
Go!
快走
Come on!
不
No!
這邊
Here
慢著 慢著 不不 中國人 中國人
Slow down! No, no! We're Chinese
- 快走 - 土豆
- Go, go! - Tundu!
走 走
Go, go, go!
走狗去死 紅巾軍必勝
Die! Scum! Hail the revolution!
走狗該死
Die! Scum!
去死
- 去死吧 - 把槍放下
- Die! - Lower your guns!
放下武器
Put down your weapons!
把槍放下 把槍放下
Lower your guns! Lower your guns!
大家暫停
Stand down!
我們是中國人
We are Chinese!
中國和非洲都是朋友
China and Africa are friends!
走
Go
走 快走 走
Go, hurry. Go.
走
Go.
撤
Fall back!
幫忙
Help! Help!
首長 他國戰艦已經全部駛離戰鬥區
Commander, all foreign vessels are leaving the war zone.
前方很危險 我們還要繼續進港嗎?
The harbor is unsafe. Are you certain about docking?
前進十
Forward 10 knots.
航向270
Set course bearing for 270.
開閘門
Open the gate!
老樊 辛苦了 你們海軍來的太及時了
Well done, you got here just in time
- 現在局勢怎麼樣?- 這個國家的叛亂完全爆發了
- What's the situation? - The entire country's in chaos.
我們僑民的生命和財產受到嚴重危害
The war has destroyed lives of many of countrymen.
你們能不能派兵把他們保護出來
Can you send our troops in to help?
未經聯合國允許
Without the UN's authorization,
我方作戰人員是不能進入的
our troops aren't premitted  to enter the war zone.
您慢點 62號
OK, slow, No.62
來來來 往上走 好
Go go go, Up we go! Nice!
你哪的?這不能上
Where are from? He can't board.
我兒子
He's my son.
我們有票 看
We have tickets. See, look!
三張 79 80 81
Three tickets. 79, 80, 81.
好 79 89 30
Fine then. 79, 80, 81.
謝謝
Thank you.
我們去哪?
Where are we going?
總理先生 你聽我說
Mr. Prime Minister, please listen to me.
貴國發生這樣的事情 我很遺憾
I'm deeply sorry for what's happening in your country.
但是我相信 你也一定不會忘記
But I believe you have not forgotten about the help,
歷史上我國對貴國的援助之情
we provided to your country
我們兩國之間的友誼
and friendship between our countries
我相信你也知道
I believe you understand how important
我國援非的陳博士對非洲的重要性
our citizen Dr. Chen is to Africa.
請派兵保障陳博士的安全
Please send somebody to protect his safety.
對不起
I'm sorry,
- 你們現在只能靠自己了 - 總理先生
- you're on your own this time - Prime Minister
陳博士在哪?
Where's Dr. Chen?
我絕不會
I will never
告訴你的
tell you
我們走
Let's go!
十二年的臥薪嚐膽啊
12 years of hard work.
一朝戰亂 全他媽沒了
One war, and it's all fucking gone
這子彈...
The bullet...
有什麼故事麼?
what's the story?
土豆
Tundu!
土豆 下了船就不能上船了啊
Tundu! If you get off, you can't get back on.
土豆 土豆
Tundu! Tundu!
- 站住 - 對不起 對不起
- Stop right there! - I'm sorry, I'm sorry
我要我媽媽
I want my mom!
我要我媽媽 我不要去中國
I want my mom, I don't want to go to China!
- 你看著我 - 我要我媽媽
- Look at me - I want my mom!
相信乾爹
I want my mom!
- 相信乾爹 - 兄弟
- Ok? I want my mom! - Hey brother
你怎麼也下來了?
What are you doing down here?
有一件事情我必須跟你說實話
There's something I have to tell you.
你戴的這個子彈...
That bullet...
我見過 這上面的花紋
I've seen it before. That pattern,
好像是反政府武裝那邊的一個什麼標記
is a symbol used by the rebel forces.
我有一個搞軍火的朋友跟我說
An arm dealer friend of mine told me
他們現在已經雇傭了歐洲價最高的雇傭兵
the rebels have hired the most expensive mercenaries out of Europe.
我不管你跟他們有什麼恩怨
Whatever grudge you've got against them,
我勸你一句
I urge you,
- 別去送死 - 桑庫加鎮的華資工廠
- don't go seeking death. - 47 Chinese workers!
還有四十七名中國員工
are still stuck at the Hanbond Chinese factory
更可怕的是五十五公里外
What's worse, Dr, Chen is stuck 55 km
還有援非小組的陳博士
behind enemy lines on a medical relief mission
他可是恐怖分子的頭號目標
He's a high value target for the rebel army.
從洛奇諾到聖佛蘭已經全面封鎖
Everything is in total lockdown from Lochino to St. Francis.
沒有聯合國的允許
Without UN's authorization,
我方作戰人員禁止進入交戰區
my troops aren't allowed to enter the war zone.
這次撤僑行動 事關重大
This operation is highly important!
我們必須讓所有的中國員工
We have to evacuate those Chinese workers!
還有陳博士安全撤離
and Dr. Chen by all means!
在目前情況下 作戰人員禁止進入交戰區
Under current circumstances, combat troops are prohibited from entering the warzone!
但我們要堅決完成撤僑
In order to complete the evacuation,
必須要一個人單獨完成任務
someone has to undertake the mission alone!
- 我去 - 站住
- I'll go. - Stop right there!
幹什麼的
What's your purpose?
原中國人民解放軍東南軍區
Former PLA, South-east region,
特種作戰旅 戰狼中隊
Specail Ops Brigade,  Wolf Warrior squadron,
冷鋒
Leng Feng.
這孩子的媽媽就在那家華資工廠
This child's mother is  at Hanbond Chinese factory.
我大概知道那裡的位置
I know approximately where it is located.
我保證
I promise you,
我會帶你媽媽回來的
I will bring your mom back.
我們已經替你搞定了
We took care of business now, didn't we?
外交部的湯特使 安德拉親王 德魯王子
Ambassador Thomas, King Angola, Prince Drew.
該死的通訊部經理
That goddamn communications manager.
他們都消失了
They're all gone. They all disappeared,
神秘的失蹤
real mysterously!
不要用這些破事糊弄我
Stop wasting my time with that crap!
陳博士在哪兒?
Where's Dr. Chen?
啊 天呐
Ah, Jesus.
告訴他 你剛對我說的
You tell him what you told me.
陳博士
Dr. Chen
在聖佛蘭華資醫院
is at St. Francis Chinese-invested hospital.
乖孩子
Good boy.
聽到了麼?
Did you hear that?
那也有可能是你的下場
That could be sound of the future.
我們為什麼要收紅巾軍那幫蠢貨的錢?
Sir, Why are we helping these fucking idiots?
歡迎來到非洲 小子
Welcome to Africa, son.
夥計們出發
Alrights, let's move out boys!
我們得到最新消息
From the latest report,
戰火已經蔓延到桑薩雷姆港口
the fighting is reaching Semshalemu harbour.
那裡等待救援的一千五百三十六名中國同胞的生命
The urgency of the evacuating 1536 Chinese nationals wating there
變得危在旦夕
has just been escalated.
撤僑軍艦必須全速趕往
Our vessels are heading over at top speed.
很抱歉 因為是別國交戰區
My apologies, because the conflict is on foreign soil,
你這次的行動沒有支援
you'll have no reinforcements,
沒有盟軍 也沒有武器
no allies and no weapons.
陳博士 還有四十七名中國同胞
Dr. Chen and 47 Chinese workers,
都帶回來
evacuate them all.
我老闆交代我
My boss asked me
找陳博士
to find Dr. Chen.
你們沒人有任何反應
Nobody wants to do something!
現在 那我只能試試運氣了
Now, I have to try my luck.
因為
Because
我有
I have
特殊的眼力
a special vision.
我猜猜...
Let me guess...
你是陳博士嗎?
Are you Dr. Chen?
- 我不是 我不是 - 你是陳博士嗎?
- I'm not! I'm not! - Are you Dr. Chen?
- 你是陳博士嗎?- 不不不
- Are you Dr. Chen? - No, no, no.
你嚇到她了 她還是個孩子
She's a child, just a child
- 我是 - 不
- I am - No
不要
No
我是陳博士
I'm Dr. Chen.
你是陳博士?
You are Dr. Chen?
陳博士怎麼沒蛋蛋了
Looks like Dr. Chen doesn't have balls.
你想要什麼?
What do you want?
- 我就是 - 瑞秋醫生 不
- I am Dr. Chen. - Dr. Rachel, no!
她不是陳博士
She's not Dr. Chen.
她是非常好的醫生
She's a very good doctor.
她救過很多人
She saved so many lives.
天啊 不要
No!
陳博士
Dr. Chen!
爸爸
Papa!
你剛殺了
You just killed
陳博士
Dr. Chen.
- 爸爸 - 陳博士
- Papa! - Dr. Chen!
陳博士是吧?
Dr. Chen, right?
我是樊大使派來救你們的
I was sent by Ambassador Fan to rescue you.
這是我的女兒帕莎
This is my daughter, Pasha.
求你務必保護好她
Please, I beg you, protect her.
陳博士
Dr. Chen!
跟我走
Come with me!
上車
Get in the car!
向東走
Go east!
你想幹嘛?
What are you doing?
你以為我在幹嘛?我在救你小命
What do you think I'm doing? I'm saving your ass!
我來開車
Let me drive!
讓開
Move!
媽了
What the hell!
掉頭
Turn around!
快快快
Go, go, go!
神經
Jesus.
帕莎
Pasha!
你沒事吧?
Are you okay?
沒事
Yeah.
帕莎
Pasha.
站住
Stop!
你們要糧食嗎?我們有糧食
You want food? We have food.
我們有糧食
We have food, okay?
We have food.
你沒事吧
Are you okay?
謝謝
Thank you.
是隔離區受的傷嗎?
Is that from quarantine zone?
把藥箱遞給我
Pasha, can you please hand me the bag?
我說是隔離區受的傷嗎?
I said, did you get that in the quarantine zone?
- 沒關係 - 你別覺得我大驚小怪啊
- It's nothing. - I'm not overreacting.
沒有狀況最好
In fact, it's better if I was.
剛才那些人感染的是拉曼拉病毒
Those people back there were infected with the Lamanla virus.
感染者很快就會出現發熱
Symptoms include the sudden onset fever,
幻覺 潰爛
hallucinations, lesions,
虛汗等症狀 是一種通過接觸傳播的非常罕見的烈性病毒
cold sweats. It's a fatal virus that's transmitted  through direct human contact.
從發病到死亡 最長五個月 最短四個小時
Upon contraction, death strikes between four hours and five months.
而且到現在 還沒有研製出能治癒這種病毒的疫苗
Up until now, no cure has been found.
沒事 我買醫保了
Don't worry, I'm insured.
你殺了中國人
You're killing the Chinese?
麻煩大了
This is a big trouble.
你為什麼殺中國人?
Why are you killing the Chinese?
- 頭兒... - 你一直想要得到陳博士
- Sir... - I thought you wanted Dr. Chen.
恭喜你 你得到他了
Congratulations. You found him.
媽的
Fuck!
我要的是活人
I wanted him alive!
活人
alive!
難道你不知道他對我有多重要嗎?
Don't you understand how important it is to me?
媽的
Fuck!
等等
Wait.
這個女孩
That girl.
我喜歡她
I like her.
頭兒 我們歐洲總部剛傳來面部識別結果
Sir, our facial recognition crew uploaded video of this man fighting off some of the pirates.
這人叫冷
His name's Leng.
曾供職於中國某神秘特種部隊
Ex-member of a secretive special ops unit pot of China.
戰狼
Wolf Warrior.
夥計們
Boys!
援非醫療小組已被武裝分子屠殺
The Doctors Without Borders were killed by armed mercenaries.
陳博士和其他中方醫護人員已經犧牲了
The lives of Dr. Cheng and other Chinese medical staff were scarificed.
冷鋒同志
Comrade Leng,
你能對你說的話負責嗎?
do you stand by what are you're saying?
你能確認親眼看見雇傭兵槍殺我國醫護人員和僑民嗎?
Are you certain you witnessed the massacre or our medical team?
我確定
I'm cetain.
在犧牲前 陳博士把他的女兒交給我
Dr. Chen give me his daughter before he died.
一個黑人小姑娘
An African girl.
叫帕莎 還有一個女護士
Her name is Pasha. Oh, and anurse too.
你叫什麼?
What's your name?
Rachel Prescott Smith 你可以叫我瑞秋
Rachel Prescott Smith. You can call me Rachel.
還有是瑞秋醫生 不是護士
Doctor Rachel, I'm not a nurse.
把所有情況立即向樊大使彙報
Report the situation to Ambassador Fan immediately.
是
Yes sir.
首長 我兒子呢?
Commander, may I speak to  my son please?
乾爹 我媽媽在哪?乾爹 我媽媽在哪?
Godfather, godfather! Where's my mom? Where's my mom?
土豆 相信乾爹
Hey, Tundu, Tundu! Trust me, Trust your godfather.
我現在正在開往漢邦工廠
We are going to Hanbond Chinese factoty
到那裡去接你媽媽 OK
to find your mom right now, okay?
謝謝乾爹
Thank you, godfather.
冷鋒 有一個非常不好的消息通知你
Leng, I have some bad news for you.
紅巾軍正在大肆毀壞重要的公路
The rebel army is sobotaging all major roads,
鐵路以及橋樑
railways and bridges.
就在十分鐘以前
As of 10 minutes ago,
從華資工廠通向碼頭的波爾尼加橋
your only route to the port, the Bowerneja bridge,
已被炸斷 我和樊大使正在全力想辦法
was bombed. We are formulating an escape plan now.
但現在只能靠你自己了
But untill then, you're on your own.
從現在開始 我們最多只能等你十八小時
Set your watch. The macimum time we can wait is 18 hours.
然後軍艦就必須返航
After that, we'll be forced to leave.
非常非常抱歉
my deepest apologies.
我必須對全體僑民負責
I have the responsibility to everyone onboard.
明白
I understand.
你要去華資工廠嗎?
You're going to the Chinese factory?
我認為我們更應該去美國領事館
We should go to the Ameriacn Consulate.
那裡有海軍陸戰隊 是全世界最安全的地方
The US marines are stationed there. That's our safest bet.
海軍陸戰隊是世界上最好的特種部隊
You think the US marines are the best in the world?
他們怎麼沒來接你啊?
That may be true, but where are they now?
我已經通知過他們了
I've informed the  consulate of the situation.
人呢?
Where are they?
你通知他們的方式是?
Tell me exactly how you informed them?
我@了他們的推特帳號
I tweeted at them on Twitter.
歡迎致電美國領事館
Welcome to American Consulate.
很不幸 我們已經閉館了
Unfortunately, we are closed.
媽的
Fuck!
我來的時候各國軍艦都已經撤離了
All foreign navy ships have left when I arrived.
當我站在碼頭上向海面眺望
A I watch them sail away from port.
無數遠去的桅杆中
Among the countless departing masts.
我看到一面星條旗
I saw one with the stars and stripes.
停車
Stop the car.
Stop the car!
停車 我要下車 停
Stop the car, I want to get out! Stop!
瑞秋
Rachel.
海軍陸戰隊接你來了
Your GIs are here to get you.
我是中國人
I'm Chinese.
我來找內莎
I'm here for Nessa.
土豆的媽媽
Tundu's mom.
內莎
Nessa!
有人嗎?
Anyone home?
我是來救你們的
I've been sent here to rescue you.
是樊大使讓我來的
By Ambassador Fan himself.
你?
You?
救我們?
Rescue us?
我這有18杆 AK
I've got 18 AK-47s.
30枚79式手雷
30 M79 grenade launchers,
夠武裝一個加強排了吧?
enough to arm a platoon.
現在一把M1911抵在你頭上
I have a M1911 pointed at your head right now.
你他媽怎麼救我們啊?
How the fuck are you supposed  to rescue us?
冷 冷 你是不是冷?
Leng, Leng! Are you Leng?
你是不是冷
Are you Leng?
- 內莎?- 是 是
- Nessa? - Yes, yes, yes!
- 我兒子怎麼樣了?- 他很安全
- What about my son? - He's safe.
- 他沒事吧?- 他沒事
- He's okay? - He's okay.
謝天謝地
Oh, thank god!
他沒事
He's okay.
媽媽 我沒事
Mom, mom, I'm ok, I'm ok!
- 謝謝老天 - 媽 我沒事 你怎麼樣
- Oh, thank god! - Mom, I'm ok!
你在中國軍艦上
Because you're on a Chinese warship.
我早就告訴你不要賣毛片
I told you, not to sell that porn.
來了 在非洲絕對找不到這麼好吃的餃子
Here we go.You definitely won't find better dumplings in Africa.
這是我從中國帶來的大廚
I flew in a chef from China.
- 親自給你們做的 - 謝謝
- Fresh, just for you. - Thank you.
看什麼呢?見過嗎?
What are you looking at? Seen one before?
玩過這槍嗎?
Ever shot one of these?
這狼啊
This wolf here,
就是我用這槍打的
I killed myself with this gun.
這地圖誰做的?
Who drew this map?
這是我指導我們家保衛幹事老何做的
I instructed our head of security, Laohe, how to do it.
還有幾個地沒修改好
It still needs some work.
老何 來 過來一下
Laohe, come here for a second.
從A區到D區
Sector A to Sector D.
這個地我已經說過很多遍了
I've told you so many times.
為什麼沒有修改過來
Why isn't it done yet?
- 馬上就改 - 老何
- I'll get on it right away.  - Laohe,
趕緊拿筆記一下
write it down quickly.
你還保安隊長 這要是實施起來出了問題
As our head of security. What if something happens during the operation?
怎麼辦?
Then what?
男人就該玩這個
This is a real man's toy.
別怕 從現在開始你的安全
Don't be afraid. From now on, your safety
- 由我來負責 - 冷 謝謝你
- will be my responsibilty. - Leng, thank you!
- 別客氣 - 非常感謝
- You're welcome. - Thank you so much!
別客氣
You're welcome.
謝謝你
Thank you.
小寶貝 這個特別好吃
Hey, kiddo. It's super yummy
試一下
try this.
- 你這孩子 - 沒事 幹嘛呢你?
- Hey! You brat! - I'm fine. What's the big deal?
人這孩子挺可愛的
I think she's kind of cute.
好消息
Good news.
樊大使打來的電話 明天上午七點
Ambassador Fan just called. Tomorrow 07:00 AM,
聯合國一架救援直升機
A UN rescue helicopter
準時在工廠降落 幫助我們撤離
will be landing at this factory to evacuate us.
一架?
Just one?
各位請注意
Attention please.
所有人
Everybody.
所有人聽我說
Everybody listen to me.
大家都安靜
Quiet down everyone.
聽我說 所有中國人全都站到這一邊兒
Listen to me. All Chinese employees, stand on this side.
我們只帶中國人 第一批管理層優先
We are only taking Chinese people. Management goes first.
我帶大家走
I will lead the evacuation.
明白嗎?所有非洲人站在這邊
Is that clear? All the Africans please stand this side, please.
明白了嗎?
Clear?
哈裡
Harry.
- 不 老闆 - 拜託
- No, boss, no. - Please.
開始動起來
Come on, come on.
動起來
Get moving.
還有呢?都往那邊去 往那邊去
Anyone else? Come, move. That side. That side.
- 你怎麼回事啊?- 俺老婆她懷孕了
- What are you doing? - She's my wife. She's pregnant
你看看
Look
還有中國人嗎?
Any more Chinese?
Any other Chinese?
老林 你給我聽好了
Lin, listen to me.
都是我們家員工
Everyone here is my employee.
我都要帶走
I'm taking them all with me.
怎麼帶啊?
How?
別停下來 別停下來
Come on, come on! Don't stop, get moving.
這邊是
Get moving. For this side,
非洲同胞
Fellow African.
- 這邊是 中國人 - 我老婆嫁給我了
- Chinese people, this side. - She married me.
就是中國人 我要把她帶走
so she's is one of us.
走 走
Move, move.
你...
You...
沒事 你就站那吧 這兒挺好
Fine, stay there. There's perfect.
來來來 男士們動一動
Come on! Come on! Guys, guys please, please move.
請站到那邊
Stand that side, please.
非洲同胞們 拜託
Please, African friends.
相信我
Trust me.
(唇語) 謝謝你 我兒子就拜託你了
(唇語)求你了
來 快一點
Come on, hurry uo, get moving.
- 你滾開 你滾開 - 別碰我
- You want to be on this side, yeah? - Fuck off, bro!
幹嘛你?
What's up?
為什麼?
Why?
中間給我讓出一條線來
Give a line down the middle.
我要看清楚一道分界線
I want to see a clear boundary line.
讓我看見那條線
A line, please
飛機是我帶來的
I brought the helicopter.
大家聽我的
I call the shots.
明天大家一起走
Everyone leaves tomorrow.
婦女兒童上飛機
Children and women leave with the chopper.
男人跟我走
The men will follow me on foot.
所有人
Everybody.
我們一起走
We leave together.
老師傅 門口那口袋
Old timer, the defensive formation out front,
您布的吧?
that was you, right?
你也不錯
You're not bad yourself.
原中國人民解放軍 西南軍區十四集團軍
Former People's Liberation Army of China, 14th Corps, South-West region,
偵察連連長 何建國
Recon Company Commander, He JianGuo.
原中國人民解放軍 東南軍區特種作戰旅
Former People's Liberation Army, Special Ops Birgade, South-East region,
戰狼中隊 冷鋒
Wolf Warrior Squadron, Leng Feng.
班長好
At your service.
敬班長
Drink in your honor.
這些人一小時前
An hour ago, these people
還不知道能不能活到明天
didn't know if they'd live to see tomorrow.
- 怎麼那麼開心啊?- 這幫黑哥們
- Why are they so happy? - Our African friends,
無論什麼戰爭啊
it doesn't matter if it's war,
瘟疫啊 貧窮啊
disease or poverty,
你只要給他們一堆火 他們立刻就這樣
once they're around the bonfire, all their cares go away.
非洲啊 吃的好
Africa. Great food.
景好
Nice scenery.
妞嘚
Hot women.
嘿
Hey.
- 乾杯 - 乾杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
我不願意一輩子活在我爸的光環之下
I don't want to ride my father's coat tail all my life.
你看看這多好啊
I love this place!
有獅子有鱷魚
Lions, crocodiles,
有AK 有狙
AK-47s, sniper rifles,
有和平地帶一輩子都聽不到的炮火之聲
and the melody of gunfire you can't get in a peaceful country.
那是這個世界上最美妙的聲音
That's the most wonderful  sound in the world.
你知道今天帕莎為什麼咬你嗎?
Do you want to know why Pasha bit you today?
因為他爸爸就是被你喜歡的AK打死的
Because her father was killed AK-47s you so adore.
如果這個是你
If this were you,
你還覺得美妙嗎?
would you still thinl it's wonderful??
天呐 你看
Oh man, look at this.
好大一個晚會
That's a big party.
我太喜歡了
I love these things.
瞧他們的樣子
Look at them.
媽的
Fuck!
帕莎
Pasha!
媽的
Shit!
放開我
Let me go!
把那個老兵除掉 雅典娜幹掉那個老傢伙
Take out the veteran. Athena,take out the old man.
待在這兒
Stay here!
放開她
Let her go!
帕莎
Pasha!
不自量力
Like ants when you lift a rock.
媽的
Fuck!
救我
Help me!
我腿受傷了
They got my leg!
你沒事兒
You're fine.
媽的
Shit!
走
Go!
走 走
Go! Go!
換彈夾
I need a reload!
走
Go!
你想幹什麼?
What are you doing, man?
媽的
Fuck!
分頭走
Let's split up!
去 去
Go! Go!
媽的
Damn it.
- 來啊 - 快走
- Come on! - Let's go!
帕莎
Pasha.
帕莎 你在哪?
Pasha, where are you?
滾開 臭婆娘
Move out of the way, bitch!
快走
Run!
你已經不是軍人了
We know you're not a soldier anymore.
他媽的還那麼拼幹嘛?
What the fuck are you fighting for?
一朝是戰狼
Once a Wolf Warrior
終生是戰狼
always a Wolf Warrior!
大熊先鋒
Bear, you're on point.
雅典娜封住所有出口 這個混蛋我要定了
Athena, cover the exit. I want this son of a bitch.
C隊發現目標 正在追
Team Charlie, spotted target. We are in pursuit.
頭兒 B隊發現目標在前方
Sir, Team Bravo has target 12 o'clock.
媽的 這幫蠢貨現在讓我們撤退
What the fuck? Those idiots want us to retreat now?
我是奧杜將軍
This is General Actu
所有人馬上撤離
everyone return to base.
馬上撤離
Return to base.
老爹 我他媽命令你立即給我滾回來
Big Daddy, I'm ordering you to get the fuck back here now!
你他媽的在做什麼?
Hey! What the fuck are you doing?
我他媽的跟你說了多少遍?
I told you so many fucking times
我們不能殺中國人
that we cannot kill the Chinese!
中國是聯合國常任理事國之一
China is a permanent member of the UN Security Council.
我們奪取政權後還要得到中國的承認
And I need them on my side if I am to take political power.
你他媽個蠢貨
You fucking asshole!
殺掉冷 抓到帕莎
Kill Leng, and find Pasha,
你將會是這個國家的主人
and you'll be the king of this fucking country
遵命 主人
As you comment, sir!
- 等等 - 冷鋒
- Hold it! - Leng Feng!
你到底什麼人?
Who are you?
- 剛一起打完仗你幹嘛呢?- 凡哥
We just fought a battle together, what's your deal? - Brither Fan
咱們這本來很安全
we were pretty safe before he got here.
他一來了反叛軍就來了
Ever wonder why the rebels show up
你們不覺得很奇怪嗎?
after he got here?
他是我兒子的朋友
He's a friend of my son.
他是來接我的
He came here for me.
- 你之前見過他嗎?- 我孩子天天都提起他
- Have you met him before? - My son always talks about him.
那又怎樣?
So?
我相信他 他今天上午在醫院就救過我和帕莎
I trust him! He rescued Pasha and me earlier today at the hospital
之後他也一直在保護我們
He's been protecting us ever since.
如果我沒理解錯的話
Let me get this straight.
你見他的時候正是你的朋友陳博士死的時候
You met him the same time your doctor friend died?
他一出現就開始死人 而他自己卻什麼事都沒有
People are getting killed around him, while he's unscathed.
朋友 你自己說說吧?
Friend, speak for yourself.
別攔著我
get off me!
- 拉曼拉 - 拉曼拉?
- Lamanla (Virus). - Lamanla?
他得了拉曼拉
He has Lamanla!
老林 他是我朋友
Lin! He's my friend.
他剛才救了我的命
He just saved my life.
他 他們怎麼辦?
What about them?
他們怎麼辦 上個月
What about them? Last month,
十公里之外的通訊中心
The comms center10 km away,
一個人得了拉曼拉 最後全廠都他媽死絕了
one person got Lamanla. In the end, the whole place was wiped out.
這可是整廠人的性命啊
Everyone's life is at stake here.
我說的這些話並不是我一個人的意思
look , it is not just my opinion.
不信你可以問他們
Ask them yourself.
我走
I'll leave.
等等
Wait.
你們知道所有得了拉曼拉病毒的人都會很快死去
You all know what will happen to someone infected with Lamanla.
我希望你們永遠記得
I hope you'll always remember
這將死的人救了你們所有人
this dying man saved all of you.
你真可恥
Shame on you!
你們所有人都可恥
Shame on all of you!
冷鋒
Leng Feng!
- 你開槍有多大把握 - 百分之五十
- How confident are you with a gun? - So-50%
在我這兒沒有那百分之五十
There's no place in my team for so-50%.
您是想讓我酒後吐真言呐
Trying to get me drunk so I blurt out the truth?
你會吐真言嗎?
Will you blurt out the truth?
會
Certainly.
你喝醉了啥樣?
What are you like when you're drunk?
我等你回來請我喝酒
I'll let you buy me drinks when you come back.
你沒回來
You're the one who didn't come back.
你回來
Come back to bed.
別鬧
Cut it out.
希望我回來的時候
When I get back
你能在這個檔上簽字
this had better be signed.
沖上去被打死很容易
It's an easy death when you're on the attack.
難的是背負著內疚和使命感繼續活下去
but it's a hard life carrying a survivor's guilt.
是你沒回來
But you didn't come back.
你沒回來
It's you who didn't come back.
You didn't come back.
到底是誰?
Against who?
昨天跟我們交的手
Who were we fighting yesterday?
你媽媽沒告訴你
Didn't your mom tell you that
小孩子不要玩槍嗎?
you shouldn't play with a gun?
冷
Leng!
就是冷 就是他一個人
That was Leng, only him alone.
是我
It was me!
我在這工作之前是個軍人
I was in the military before I worked here.
你看看其他人
Does anyone here
像會開槍射擊的樣子嗎?
look like they can shoot?
好啊
Okay.
你醒了
You're up.
可惜陳博士沒有看到這一幕
It's a shame Dr. Chen didn't live to see this.
他是全世界唯一發現自愈活體的專家
He discovered the presence of self-healing properties in humans.
陳博士發現有極少數人體內有抵抗拉曼拉的抗體
In extreme rare cases, Lamanla antibodies can be found in patients.
在他無數次和拉曼拉患者的治療過程中
Among the thousands of Lamanla patients he treated
他偶然發現了一個自愈活體的實例
He chanced upon one such person
而這個自愈活體就是帕莎
And that person is Pasha.
她不是陳博士的女兒 是他的病人
So Pasha's not his daughter, but his patient.
陳博士通過對帕莎血液成分的分析和萃取
From the analysis of Pasha's blood
剛剛研製出一種新藥
he created an experimental vaccine.
昨天晚上因為情況緊急
Last night was a dire situation,
我只能在你身上做了一個陳博士曾經設想
so I experimented on you, what Dr. Chen was planning to do.
但是還沒來得及做的活體實驗
The first human trial that he was hoping for
我把陳博士的新藥注射到了你的身上
Injecting you with Dr. Chen's newly synthesized vaccine immunogens
說實話
Honestly speaking,
那個時候我真不知道會發生什麼
I didn't know what would happen.
幸運的是
Luckily
上帝站在我們這邊
God was on your side.
這個國家人民看到政府對病毒的無能為力極度失望
The population has lost faith in the government to contain the outbreak.
所以 誰得到帕莎
So, whoever takes Pasha
誰就能輕易的掌控這個國家
takes the country easily.
怪不得反政府軍一直在追殺我們
That explains why the rebel army is hot on our heels.
我爸爸說十萬年前人類走出非洲
My dad said man walked out of Africa 100.000 years ago.
非洲是現代文明的搖籃
Africa is the cradle of modern civilization.
可是當自詡文明的人們再次來到非洲
Yet when the "evolved, civilized" humans returned to this land,
帶來的卻是苦難
they brought along with them nothing but suffering,
奴役 疾病和戰爭
slavery, disease and war.
韓國人 冰島人 斯拉夫人
Koreans, Icelanders, Slavs,
美國人
Americans
那些是中國人 他們都是來自世界各地的
and over there are Chinese. People from all over the world,
像我爸爸一樣的人
people like my father.
為了非洲
For Africa
他們付出了自己的青春
they gave their best years.
到最後
In the end,
把自己永遠地留在這片土地
they got to remain here for eternity.
她叫什麼名字
What's her name?
嗯?
Huh?
那個你忘不了的人
The person you can't seem to forget.
龍小雲
Long XiaoYun.
她好幸運
She's lucky
有一個這麼愛她的男人
to have a man that loves her so much.
她為什麼沒有回來呢?
Why didn't she come back?
對不起
Sorry.
把他們當作餃子給我包起來 讓他們以為是安全的 明白嗎?
I want you to round 'em up like cattle. Make 'em feel safe. You understand me?
收到
Yes, sir.
東邊是山區
We got mountains to the west,
西邊是雨林 如果他夠聰明 就會來這等直升機
we got forests to the east. The only smart place for them to come is right here and wait for the rescue helicopter.
中國佬 你可別死
I sure hope these Chinese people don't die.
能救你的只有我了
I'm about the only thing that can save them right now.
全體集合
Round 'em up.
所有人準備出發 出發 出發 出發 出發
Everybody, let's go! Let's go! Move, move, move!
等我他媽出去了
Wait till I get out of here,
我他媽絕對不會放過這幫孫子
I'm going to settle the score with them.
凡哥
Brother Fan,
別他媽吹牛逼了
cut the fucking bullshit.
怎麼出去啊?
How are we going to get out?
再說了 您出去能幹什麼呀?
And besides, what are you planning to do?
您會什麼呀?
What can you even do?
凡哥
Brother Fan,
平時我們都讓著你
in normal times, everyone gives in to you.
打起仗來 沒人會讓著我們
In battle, no one will be giving in to us.
給我閉嘴
Shut the fuck up!
去死吧
Go to hell!
哥 撐得住嗎?
Brother, how are you holding up?
比以前差遠了
Not as well as back in the day.
你的手是用來救人的 不是用來殺人的
Your hands are for saving lives not taking lives.
這種仗戰狼會怎麼打
How would Wolf Warriors fight this battle?
走
Go!
你媽媽沒告訴你小孩子不要玩槍嗎?
Didn't your mom tell you not to play with weap?
你媽沒告訴你別欺負熊孩子嗎?
Didn't your mom tell you not to fuck with spoiled brats?
走啦
Let's go!
這就是雇傭軍與反叛軍屠殺我國僑民的證據
Here's evidence of the rebel  army killing our citizens.
收到 我們馬上把資料匯總
Transmission received. We will gather up all the information,
讓樊大使儘快遞交聯合國
and have Ambassador Fan submit it to the UN.
明白
Copy that.
另外 當地政府已經向我國正式請求軍事援助
oh and one more thing. The local government has critically requested for our military assistance
直升機馬上就到
The chopper will arrive shortly
- 我們等你回家 - 好
- We're waiting for you. - Copy that!
- 你趕緊上飛機 - 還有很多人需要我説明
- Get on the chopper - There're a lot of people here who still need me.
林志雄
Lin Zhi Xiong!
- 女人孩子都得上飛機 - 在這裡我不是女人我是醫生
- Women and childern must get on the chopper. - Right now I'm not a woman. I'm a doctor
論救援 我比你專業
The more professional than you when it comes to saving lives.
論保護人我比你專業
But I'm more professional than you in protecting lives!
帕莎 你準備好坐直升機了嗎?
Pasha, are you ready to get on the helicopter?
遞一些紗布給我
Can you pass me some gauze please?
快上直升機
Get on the helicopter.
你別給我添亂 好不好?
Don't be difficult, okay?
- 讓一下?- 讓什麼讓
- Excuse me? - Excuse you my ass!
發生什麼事了
Whoa, what was that?
求救 求救
Mayday! Mayday!
我們被襲擊 失去尾旋翼
Missile strike! Tail rotor lost!
我還能控制 硬著陸
I have control. Going down!
求救 求救
Mayday! Mayday!
準備迫降
Brace! Brace!
- 走 走 - 走
- Go! Go! - Go!
快跑
Run!
老庫房
To the bunker!
快
Hurry!
瑞秋
Rachel!
醒醒
Wake up!
Come on! Come on!
瑞秋
Rachel!
去找老何
Go find LaoHe!
起來 快點
Get up! Come on!
媽的
Fuck!
快進老庫房
Get to the bunker!
走 快 走
Go! Quickly! Go!
走 快
Go! Quickly!
準備
Get ready!
開炮
Fire!
把那個傢伙幹掉
Kill that motherfucker!
裝彈
Reload!
我瞄不到
I can't aim.
- 這麼重 - 找死啊
- This thing's so heavy! - You wanna die!?
引信一碰 都得死
Trigger that fuse and it'll kill us all!
開炮
Fire!
哦 好極了
Oh, check it.
下三杠
Three clicks down.
發炮
Fire!
他們找到老庫房了
They found the bunker!
目標 左搖
I got it! I got it! To the left.
- 收到 - 裝彈
- Copy that. - Reload!
沒彈了
We're out!
抓穩了
Hang on!
開炮
Fire!
狗娘養的
Son of a bitch!
媽的 坦克啟動
Fuck! Move this fucking thing.
快點
Come on! Come on!
好
Good, good, good.
媽的
Fuck!
看來中國軍人沒有我想的那麼懦弱
I guess the Chinese military ain't as lame as I thought.
你丫少他媽廢話
Cut the crap.
走
Go!
快走
Hurry!
不要出來
Don't come out!
立即搜索信號 確定目標位置
Track the signals and verify targets positions!
乾爹
Godfather!
媽媽
Mom!
- 報告 手機位置鎖定 - 報告 目標鎖定
- Sir, we have triangulated on the phone's position! - Sir, targets locked on!
- 報告 我們得到上級命令 - 開火
- Sir, we recieved orders from COMMAND! - Fire!
現在是私人恩怨
Now it's personal.
龍小雲
Long XiaoYun.
那是你女人
Is that your girl?
長得很漂亮
She's pretty.
血債... 血償
Blood... for blood.
別打了
Please don't fight!
你看她們
Look at them.
沒錯 你將會為這些人而死
You're gonna die for this people.
我就是為他們而生的
I was born for them.
這個世界只有強者和弱者 你們這種劣等民族永遠屬於弱者
People like you will always be inferior to people like me
你要習慣 你必須習慣
Get used to it. Get fucking used to it.
那他媽是以前
That's fucking history.
你醒了
Welcome back.
前方是交戰區 我們過不去了
The war zone is up ahead. We can't get through.
三點方向有不明車隊
UNidentified vehicle convoy at three o'clock.
哥
Brother,
把國旗給我
pass me the flag.
開車
Drive.
是中國人 停止射擊
It's the Chinese. Hold your fire.
停止射擊 是中國人
Hold your fire! It's Chinese.
冷鋒
Leng Feng.
- 首長好 - 小日子過的挺美的呀
- Commander! - I see you're enjoying your life.
不想回戰狼了吧?
Not planning on rejoining the Wolf Warriors?
離開這裡最早的航班
Sir, the earliest flight out of here,
是下星期二 十四點十五分 星期五上午九點
departs next Tuesday at 14:15 by Friday 09:00.
我準時向您報導
I will report for duty sir!
有件事我必須告訴你
There's something I need to tell you...